Guide to the Ace Reid Accessions
The Wittliff Collections
Ace Reid Accessions
1956-1995
The Wittliff Collections https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Reid, Asa E., 1925-1991
UPWC.18157
2 boxes Plus 90 framed items and artifacts
22 Linear Feet
An extensive collection of original cowpoke artwork by Asa "Ace" Reid. The bulk of the accession consists of 75 framed pen and ink cartoons, and there are another 35 unframed in box 1. Also framed are 14 original watercolors by Reid, a 6-foot oil painting of Reid, and a banner from Ruidoso Downs. There are several photographs of Ace Reid by himself and with others, as well as photographs of notables such as Governor John Connally, Hank Thompson, and Slim Pickens. Artifacts include Reid's drawing table, chair, and saddle. The collection was transferred from the Museum of Western Art in Kerrville, Texas.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gifts of Madge Reid, 2001-2018
Biographical Note
Asa E. "Ace" Reid was the creator of the cartoon Cowpokes and a Western humorist. Cowpokes, at one time, ran in over 400 weekly newspapers across the United States. He produced many popular cartoon books and calendars during his lifetime.
He was born parents Asa E. Reid, Sr. and Callie Miles Bishopon ,Lelia Lake, Texas. Shortly after his birth, the family moved to Electra, on March 10, 1925. He grew up ranching and cowboying.
During World War II, he served as a machinist's mate in the U.S. Navy in the Pacific aboard the USS Lanier. Cowpokes was born on board the Lanier; "The Sorry Salt" was a cartoon he drew for the ship's newspaper. After the war, "The Sorry Salt" became "Jake", his primary character.
On September 11, 1949, in Dallas, he married Madge Parmley, and they moved to Kerrville, Texas, in 1952. Ace's first cartoon appeared in West Texas Livestock Weekly that same year. Two years later, their son and only child, Stan, was born. Ace and Madge were living in Kerrville at the time of his death on November 10, 1991. Madge still lives in Kerrville and has kept Cowpokes going since Ace's death.
Abstract
An extensive collection of original cowpoke artwork by Asa "Ace" Reid. The bulk of the accession consists of 75 framed pen and ink cartoons, and there are another 35 unframed in box 1. Also framed are 14 original watercolors by Reid, a 6-foot oil painting of Reid, and a banner from Ruidoso Downs. There are several photographs of Ace Reid by himself and with others, as well as photographs of notables such as Governor John Connally, Hank Thompson, and Slim Pickens. Artifacts include Reid's drawing table, chair, and saddle. The collection was transferred from the Museum of Western Art in Kerrville, Texas.
Index Terms
Subjects
Cartoonists -- United States; Cowboys -- Caricatures and cartoons; Artists -- Texas; Ranch life -- Caricatures and cartoons
- Accession 2018-157
  Abstract
  An extensive collection of original cowpoke artwork by Asa "Ace" Reid. The bulk of the accession consists of 75 framed pen and ink cartoons, and there are another 35 unframed in box 1. Also framed are 14 original watercolors by Reid, a 6-foot oil painting of Reid, and a banner from Ruidoso Downs. There are several photographs of Ace Reid by himself and with others, as well as photographs of notables such as Governor John Connally, Hank Thompson, and Slim Pickens. Artifacts include Reid's drawing table, chair, and saddle. The collection was transferred from the Museum of Western Art in Kerrville, Texas.
  - Photographs, 1965-1968, undated
    - Ace Reid at drawing table; creating watercolor of horse and cowboy similar to the drawing in framed item 072 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ace Reid on horse with saddle, badge, and leather cuffs. Photographer: Jerry Sinise, Globe-News Pub. Co, Amarillo, TX (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ace Reid in publicity photo for Mooney Aircraft; plane and saddle (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - [Ace Reid] in hat and bandana (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ladybird Johnson holding Cowpokes; Ace Reid holding A White House Diary, Keller's Studio, Fredericksburg, TX (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rex Allen and Ace Reid at the Draggin S Ranch, 1968-02-01 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ace Reid and Charlton Heston at a black-tie event (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ace Reid and Joel McCrea at a black-tie event (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ace Reid and Will Rogers, Jr. (digital print) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ace Reid in "formal attire" at Charles Schreiner Party. Man next to him is holding Cowpokes Wanted (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Charles Schreiner, Marshal House of Dodge City, and Ace Reid (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ruidoso Downs; Horse is wearing the "1st Annual Ace Reid Purse" banner, framed item 081, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Peter Hurd visits Kerrville, gathering at party. Photographer: Lafayette Reed, Kerrville (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hank Thompson portrait, signed: "To my friend – Ace Reid 'sure enjoy your cartoons!'" (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Slim Pickens, signed: "To Madge and Ace, my very best always" (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Texas Governor John Connally holding framed Ace Reid watercolor of a steer, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Billboard for the West Texas Rehab Center, Abilene, TX. "Cowpokes cartoon has been used for the 57th year" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Loose Foam-mounted Photographs, 1979, undated
    - Ace Reid, Jerry Palen (cartoonist), and Baxter Black (author, speaker), signed (Box 1)
    - Slim Pickens, Ace Reid "in the movies" (Box 1)
    - John Erickson (author, Hank the Cowdog) and Ace Reid (Box 1)
    - Ace Reid and Will Rogers, Jr. in Kerrville (Box 1)
    - Ace Reid and others at Ken Curtis "Festus" in Kerrville (Box 1)
    - Ace Reid and Kinky Friedman "No smoking event," Kerrville (Box 1)
    - Hondo [Crouch], Green Brothers, Windy Ryon of Fort Worth at Kerrville (Box 1)
    - Jerry Lackey (San Angelo Standard Times), Tumble Weed Smith (radio personality) Photographer: Enochs (Box 1)
    - Rex Allen signed, "Ace, you go to "hell" (Box 1)
    - Dahlberg (Kerrville sculptor). Signed, "To Madge and Ace, Good Friends for a long time. Many thanks", 1979 (Box 1)
  - Award: "National Cowboy Symposium and celebration: Cowboy Culture Award," Lubbock Avalanche-Journal, 1992 (Box 1)
  - 35 Original pen and ink cartoons on paper, 1956-1990, undated
    - "Boy, I bet this ole country could shore look tough in a drought!", 8 ½" x 8 ½" (Box 2)
    - "Come on in, Maw! Here's a sale on chain saws and I want you to try one for size.", 9" x 9" (Box 2)
    - "Shore, there's a future for a cowboy on this outfit…work 16 hours a day 'til you're 65 and you might get to be foreman and maybe even git your picture in the local paper…that's if you don't git crippled up too bad.", 8 ¾" x 9" (Box 2)
    - "Wul yeah, they're headin' out fer a round up…to round up lost deer hunters!", 10" x 10" (Box 2)
    - "Yes, yes, I'm gonna ride your old bronc, but I jist remembered I ain't seen my dear old Mother in eight years and I'm gonna pay her a little visit!", 9 ½" x 10" (Box 2)
    - "Now it looks like that ole boy got elected by promisin' to balance the budget and he's seven payments behind to Sears and Roebuck!", 10" x 10" (Box 2)
    - "Naw, I don't git my exercise by joggin'.. I'm always juggin!", 10" x 10" (Box 2)
    - "Now Mr. Banker, jist because you were the one that loaned me the money to buy them calves that I jist lost money on…I want you to know that I ain't made at you!", 10" x 10" (Box 2)
    - "Naw they ain't from some old folks' home…they're young folks from Ft. Worth that's been huntin here fer a week!," [possibly unpublished], November 23, 1967; 10" x 11" (Box 2)
    - Cowpoke portrait (head only), 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Reckon why the boss threw such a fit about that old cow being near the fence?", 1956; 11" x 11 (Box 2)
    - "The President is always eatin' somethin' and makin' the price go up. Reckon he couldn't help the hoss market?", 1956; 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "If you're looking for a tax write off this is the place! The tax people don't know it exist.", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Jake, come look thru these, my deer looks a lot bigger!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Looks to me like that old boy is gonna hafta quit watching them late T.V. shows er get into some other kind of work!", December 27, 1987; 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Oh, I'm shore glad it's you Sherriff! You can help us return my neighbor's cattle that some thief done put in our pickup.", 1963; 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Awright Jr., now I know why I've spent my whole life working hard to save… so in my old age I can give it to my doctor!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Whatta you mean you're wantin' a washin' machine when you know good and well I've got to buy a new saddle?", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Banker Tufernal, all them live ones is yore collateral, and the dead ones is your interest!", 1976; 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Now if I work fer $200 a month fer 5000 months, that's a million dollars. Are you sure you have that much money?", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Now look at that…time are good, grass is deep, but that no good son won't leave; makes his Maw support him and nearly starves his baby brother to death!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "I'm takin' care of im' few a friend, the first nite he got foundered, then cut a leg half off, then wuz snake bit on the nose. Now I'm bein' sued by my friend!" [pencil sketch on reverse side], January, 14, 1990; 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Quit it Jake, you know I can't stand anybody abusin' a saddle like that!", January 6, 1985; 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Wul, you're about as close to being a world's champion as you ever was!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Wul it's discouragin' when yer bookkeeper tells you how much money er losin' when yer runnin' 500 cows. Then he tells about his neighbor that runs 50 cows and jist bought a Cadillac!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Now Maw, I just finished tellin' them ole boys how sweet, tender and understandin' you were, then you made a liar out of me!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "If them ole boys would ever graze their place like us, they wouldn't have to be fightin' grass fires all the time!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "This has been a great year… the cow market and the skirts went up at the same time!" [alternate caption on back], 1967; 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "I shore wish one of you fellers would loan me a pocket knife to cut loose from this ole steer, before one of us gits hurt!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Nope, my client wuz not drinkin' when he ran off that bridge, he wuz fixin' a taco!", January 21, 1990; 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Out here we can tell which way the wind blown' jest by the way the posts are leanin'!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "It's a 'git well' card from yore banker. It sez, git well or else!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "My gosh, Zeb, we're tryin' to get the cow out! We're not tryin' to see what all we can git in here with her!", February 9, 1964; 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "Wul we have driven 24 miles to the mail box to git a notice to drive 45 miles to town, to pay 3 cents postage due on a bill from the feed store!", 11" x 11" (Box 2)
    - "They're tranquillizers! The druggist says if I can take enough of 'em, I won't even worry about sellin' my calves two months too soon fer two dollars below market price", 1958; 11" x 11" (Box 2)
  - Posters
    - West Texas Boys Ranch, San Angelo. Annual round-up (Box 2)
    - Pony Express Rider screening. Guest-starring Ken Curtis, Slim Pickens, and Ace Reid (among others in Kerrville) (Box 2)
  - Ephemera, 1994
    - Cowpokes Cartoons brochure (Box 2)
    - Visions West, with article about Ace Reid, Summer 1994 (Box 2)
    - Foam-mounted copy of the article from Visions West, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Proclamations, 1961, 1963
    - H. S. R. No. 20. Resolution commending Ace Reid "for his wit and facility and mettle and skill in depicting the Old West and in giving future generations assurance and confidence in the past to insure their trust and faith in future." Jim Nugent, Representative. Signed by James A. Turman, Speaker of the House., August 12, 1961 (Box 2)
    - H. S. R. No. 553. Resolution commending Ace Reid [same text as 1961]. Jim Nugent, Representative. Signed by Byron Tunnell, Speaker of the House., May 22, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Framed Items
    - Item 001 "Jake, I'm leaving my husband – he just don't pay…", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 002 "Jake, tell me one more time how much fun we're havin!", 15 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 003 "Let's come back some other time!", 15 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 004 "Oh, my gosh, hoss, we musta hit the back of the …", 15 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 005 "Pull him more to the left 'er your not gonna be able…", 15 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 006 "Shore he's a good fast hoss…he beats anything I've…", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 007 "The way you jist sit there a sayin' nuthin takes all the…", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 008 "To think 6 hours ago we wuz in a heck of a drought!", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 009 "What do you mean pay some more on my principle, I'm doin' well…", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 010 "Wul ole pony, at least it beats a sand storm!", 15 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 011 "Wul yeah, I can tell it's a crossbred…but with what?", 15 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 012 "Yeah, I'm gonna examine you jist as soon as I examine…", 15 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 013 "Oh me, these critters seem to know I'm getting slower every year!", 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 014 "Jist shows you ole hoss, these wide open spaces ain't always so wide!", 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 015 "Jake, Mr. Bank Examiner says that after examining your notes, he wants to examine my head!" Framed, 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 016 "When a stupid cowpoke ropes a crazy cow on an ignorant hoss, this outta happen to em!", 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 017 "Smile Jake, the audience thinks you're part of the clown act!", 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 018 "Hey, turn down that transistor radio; I think I hear a deer coming!", 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 019 "I was jist sittin' in there a swattin' flies and wul…", 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 020 "Yeah, you shore throw wide loops - - now lets see if you're gonna throw that fence back in shape." Framed, 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 021 "Banker, you said before you'd loan me any money I'd hafta bring in my book keepin' system you just don't know what heck I had takin' the barn door off!" Framed, 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 022 "This loop's big enough, I don't really want to catch 'em!", 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 023 "Wal, he wasn't much of a salesman anyhow!", 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 024 So they can shoot one another, but we'll git in a bunch of trouble if we shoot a coyote!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 025 "Aw quit naggin' at me Ma! I was gonna build a new fence anyhow!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 026 "Wilbur, if you want to lose weight so bad why don't you eat what you feed yore ole cows!" Framed, 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 027 "Don't complain, Bull. That's the road you promised last election.", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 028 "Awright Tufernal, quit callin me when I'm overdrawn _ _ _ I don't call you when I make a deposit!" Framed, 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 029 "Man, after I pay my doctor and buy new clothes I'll nearly have enough to git to the next rodeo." Framed, 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 030 "Son, I'm letting you have this loan but it's gotta be paid back in less than 500 years!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 031 "Jake, I jist guaranteed he'd jump into a trailer … _ nothing wuz said about him jumpin' out!" Framed, 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 032 "Dang, Lem, do something! She's up but I'm down!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 033 "My doctor told me to exercise a lot _ _ _ _ that a-way I can die healthier.", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 034 "Cow prices musta took a jump, the banker just tipped his hat to us.", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 035 "I just had to make a marginal land loan _ _ _ _ put in a slug of scotch in his Maalox.", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 036 "Boy, this rain is shore wonderful. Look at maw…Just overcome with joy!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 037 "Wut the skunks got my chickens, coyotes got my calfes, and the eagles got my lands_ _ won't be long till us ranchers will be the endangered species. Framed, 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 038 "I remember this as a little town _ _ _ _ before it grew up big and impersonal!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 039 "I'm sellin that ole ranch! We're makin more money pickin up cans than we do raising cows! Framed, 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 040 "Yep, Jake, it looks hopeless, but I think it's serious!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 041 "Naw I ain't give up drinkin', but after that horse race I've shore quit gamblin'! Framed, 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 042 "Naw, you didn't ride longer than anybody _ _ _ but he throwed you farther!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 043 "The only worries I ain't had on this ranch was income taxes!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 044 "Pin, would you git back and hold this calf….besides you're standing on my piggin' string!" Framed, 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 045 "Wul… I couldn't make it in the cow business so the bank financed me to a bait shop. Now the lake's gone dry." Framed, 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-1)
    - Item 046 "Now maybe them guys will understand that I want this gate closed!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 046 "Now maybe them guys will understand that I want this gate closed!" Framed, 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 047 "No use openin' that gate any wider Zep, I believe I'm the only one comin' thru!", 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 048 "My gosh, can't you understand nothin'?" I said keep that gate shut!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 049 "Gosh, fer a minute I thought he'd pulled off both of my legs!" Framed, 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 050 "You misunderstood me, I didn't say this place would run 7,000 head of cattle, I said it takes that many to pay for it." Framed, 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 051 "Even with yore soft brown eyes, it don't seem possible them hunters would take you or a deer." Framed, 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 052 "Jake, what makes this saddle a bargain is … I'm throwin' everything that's in it!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 053 "The Boss just called from Las Vegas and said, "Just repair it, can't afford to replace it." Framed, 17 x 17 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 054 "Well I guess it would be ridiculous to wrap this pipe…Now!", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 055 "This here is my "Famous Diet Breed" _ _ They give skin milk and lean meat.", 17.75 x 17.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-3)
    - Item 056 "You wanta check the fence, make shore there ain't no place calves can get out!", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 057 "It's all ole Wilburs fault…he said that we steal 'em cheaper than raisin 'em.", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 058 "Now this place is mine and that one's my bankers", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 059 "Wul, we didn't have no trouble getting' into orbit I fear the splash down is gonna be messy!" Framed, 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 060 "Act dumb", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 061 "I thought you said this wuz the happy hour!", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 062 "Wul, that ole wool was so full of seed it just took a shower to keep the milk cow fed for a few weeks." Framed, 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 063 "Clyde, you're sure lucky! The boss thinks you're the best horse shoe'r on the place!", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 064 "Wul, when you said that wuz a kid pony had no idea you meant Billy the Kid!", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 065 "Ain't it sumpin' this ole horse wont let anybody but you and Ma shoe him", 15.5 x 15.5 (Frame Annex B 7-A-2)
    - Item 066 Ace Reid sitting in his studio drawing a cartoon. Color Framed Photograph, 18.75 x 22.5 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 067 Three Cowboys, bartender and horse in bar, Cowboy drinking beer, horse eating from cowboy's lunch. Color Framed Original, 18 x 23.5 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 068 Cowboy in Western wear shop trying on boots, Salesman holding his nose. Color Framed Original, 19.75 x 23.75 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 069 Cowboy being bucked off at cooking station, chuck wagon and cook in background, 2 riders on the right. Color Framed Original, 19 x 23 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 070 Cowboy on ground under broken clothes line, Lady standing behind, horse bucking with clothesline on saddle horn. Color Framed Original, 14.75x21.5 (Frame Annex B 6-B-1)
    - Item 071 Cowboys sitting on ground eating, One cowboy on horse, Cook leaving on chuck wagon. Color Framed Original, 20 x 25 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 072 2 cartoons: left: cowboy on bucking horse holding his hat; Right: cowboy bucked off, laying on ground. Black and White Framed Original with red border, 14.5 x 23.5 (Frame Annex B 6-B-1)
    - Item 073 Cowboy riding brahma bull holding bull's tail; yellow chaps, yellow rigging. Color Framed Original (book cover), 17.5 x 16.25 (Frame Annex B 6-B-1)
    - Item 074 2 cartoons - right: Cowboy being dragged by roped steer; Left: Cowboy roped steer and rope got tangled on hind leg. Framed Black and White Red Border, 27.5 x 15 (Frame Annex B 6-B-1)
    - Item 075 Cowboy taking a bath in a puddle. Color framed original, 19.5 x 24.75 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 076 Cowboy riding right to left, jackrabbit running same direction. Color framed original, 10.5 x 24.75 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 077 Cowboys in bunkhouse taking bath shaving and cutting hair. Color framed origina, 18.5 x 22.5 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 078 Cowboy on horse bucking roped calf; cow in front of horse, rider on white horse behind. Color framed original, 17.25 x 21.75 (Frame Annex B 6-B-1)
    - Item 079 Cowboy on bucking horse at rodeo arena, #3 and 4 chutes in background. Colored framed original, 24 x 22 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 080 3 cowboys getting their picture taken; man behind camera has black and white checkered vest on. Color framed original, 22.5 x 16.5 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 081 Pink Banner (first Ace Reid annual rodeo, 1967) Ace Reid Purse, Ruidoso Downs. Framed, 22 x 36 (Frame Annex B 6-B-3)
    - Item 082 Watercolor by Ace Reid showing calf roping, dated 1953. Framed, 34 x 25 (Frame Annex B 6-B-3)
    - Item 083 Watercolor by Ace Reid, dated 1952. Madge says this painting hung in Ace's mother's house. Framed, 24.75 x 35 (Frame Annex B 6-B-3)
    - Item 084 Oil painting of Ace Reid by Lois Raymer of Kerrville. Madge Reid says this painting was commissioned to hang over her fireplace but it turned out to be two times too tall to fit into the space. Framed, 72 x 31.5 (Frame ARC)
    - Item 085 "Ma, I know you jist spent $3 gittin yre hair fixed, but you don't want me to git my $25 hat wet!" Framed, 17 x 21 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
    - Item 086 "Jist think, if fences hadn't been invented, we might be unemployed!", 17 x 21 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)